<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-07T23:03:47+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">My personal blog - Richard Huo</title><subtitle>在这里写一些文字，和大家分享NLP方向的前沿动态。
</subtitle><author><name>Richard Huo</name></author><entry><title type="html">ForeverYoung</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Forever-Young/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ForeverYoung" /><published>2018-03-11T18:32:20+08:00</published><updated>2018-03-11T18:32:20+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Forever-Young</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Forever-Young/">&lt;p&gt;If you have known what you will face in advance, will you have enough courage to come again?
From World War, to revolution and ultimately rebirth, Forever Young is the story of four generations spanning a hundred years of modern Chinese history. Each generation faces its own unique set of challenges. Up against corporate corruption, the trials and tribulations of the cultural revolution, and one’s duty to nation in time of war, they are faced with choosing their individual paths through history. But as the challenges and turmoil of each generation may differ as time changes, what was learned in the past cannot help but effect the choices that are made in the future as it is passed down from generation to generation. And that is the universal message that being true to yourself is precious. It is the source of strength that empowers one to become the person they want to be, to march forward as far as their hearts desire, into the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;font color=&quot;#EE2C2C&quot;&gt;&quot;爱你所爱，行你所行，听从你心，无问西东&quot;
&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/film-foreveryoung-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Yosh Ginsu&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ricard Huo</name></author><category term="Blog" /><category term="Forever Young" /><summary type="html">If you have known what you will face in advance, will you have enough courage to come again? From World War, to revolution and ultimately rebirth, Forever Young is the story of four generations spanning a hundred years of modern Chinese history. Each generation faces its own unique set of challenges. Up against corporate corruption, the trials and tribulations of the cultural revolution, and one’s duty to nation in time of war, they are faced with choosing their individual paths through history. But as the challenges and turmoil of each generation may differ as time changes, what was learned in the past cannot help but effect the choices that are made in the future as it is passed down from generation to generation. And that is the universal message that being true to yourself is precious. It is the source of strength that empowers one to become the person they want to be, to march forward as far as their hearts desire, into the future.</summary></entry></feed>